<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Installing GoCD on GoCD User Documentation</title>
    <link>/installation/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Installing GoCD on GoCD User Documentation</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    
	<atom:link href="/installation/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Change SSL Certificates</title>
      <link>/installation/ssl_tls/custom_server_certificate.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/installation/ssl_tls/custom_server_certificate.html</guid>
      <description>Using your own SSL certificates on the Server Note GoCD version 20.2 no longer supports configuring TLS. See this GitHub issue for more details.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Configure a Reverse Proxy</title>
      <link>/installation/configure-reverse-proxy.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/installation/configure-reverse-proxy.html</guid>
      <description>Configure a reverse proxy server to use with GoCD server It is sometimes useful to front GoCD with a proxy server. In this section, we give you some tips and examples on how to achieve this.
GoCD with Apache An example of how to configure GoCD with Apache is shown below.
Assumptions:
 You have Apache with mod_proxy installed The Apache server sits on the same machine as the GoCD server (localhost)  Listen nnn.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Configure an agent with proxy</title>
      <link>/installation/configure-agent-proxy.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/installation/configure-agent-proxy.html</guid>
      <description>Configure a GoCD agent to connect to a server through a proxy server. Note: Using this feature requires atleast version 17.11.0 of the GoCD server and agent.
Proxy support is configured with GoCD agents by passing certain system properties to the Java Virtual Machine (JVM) on startup. These properties follow the conventions defined by the JVM:
 http.proxyHost http.proxyPort (default: 80) http.nonProxyHosts (default: localhost|127.*|[::1]) https.proxyHost https.proxyPort socksProxyHost socksProxyPort (default: 1080) socksProxyVersion (default: 5)  To configure an agent to use a proxy edit the wrapper-properties.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Configuring GoCD Database</title>
      <link>/installation/configuring_database.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/installation/configuring_database.html</guid>
      <description>Configuring GoCD Database As part of GoCD release v20.5.0, GoCD introduced the ability to integrate with H2, PostgreSQL and MySQL databases.
This section describes how to bring up a new GoCD Server instance, using the database of your choice. In case you are looking to migrate the data from an existing GoCD Server instance, please take a look GoCD Database Migration documentation.
GoCD Supports following databases (with mentioned versions):  H2 (v1.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Configuring HSTS Header</title>
      <link>/installation/ssl_tls/configuring_hsts_header.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/installation/ssl_tls/configuring_hsts_header.html</guid>
      <description>Configuring the HSTS header The Strict-Transport-Security (HSTS) header can be enabled and configured using the following System Properties
   Key Default value Description     gocd.enable.hsts.header false A boolean value indicating whether the HSTS header should be enabled   gocd.hsts.header.max.age 31536000 The max-age value of the header. Defaults to one year   gocd.hsts.header.include.subdomains false Whether the include-subdomains flag should be set on the header   gocd.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Configuring Server Details</title>
      <link>/installation/configuring_server_details.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/installation/configuring_server_details.html</guid>
      <description>Configuring GoCD server details Artifact repository configuration GoCD needs no configuration once installed. However, we recommend that you create a separate partition on your computer&amp;rsquo;s hard disk for GoCD server artifacts. The artifact repository can grow in size very quickly. If located on your system&amp;rsquo;s main partition you may experience data loss and unpredictable application behaviour as the disk fills up.
Once you have created a new disk partition, you need to tell GoCD where to find it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Configuring SSL/TLS</title>
      <link>/installation/ssl_tls_config.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/installation/ssl_tls_config.html</guid>
      <description>  CONFIGURING SSL/TLS    </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Customizing Ciphers</title>
      <link>/installation/ssl_tls/setting_up_ciphers.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/installation/ssl_tls/setting_up_ciphers.html</guid>
      <description>Configuring SSL/TLS ciphers You can choose which ciphers and SSL/TLS protocols GoCD will use for communication with agents and users (and their browsers)
Configuring GoCD server Note GoCD version 20.2 no longer supports configuring TLS. See this GitHub issue for more details.
To configure SSL, please install and configure a reverse proxy to terminate SSL.
Configuring GoCD agent The default transport protocol that the GoCD uses to communicate with GoCD server is determined by the version of Java that runs with the agent.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Enabling GoCD to use H2 Database</title>
      <link>/installation/configuring_database/h2.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/installation/configuring_database/h2.html</guid>
      <description>Enabling GoCD to use H2 Database  GoCD installers ship with H2 database and no external configuration is required to use GoCD with H2 database. Troubleshooting Database is read-only You might see a message such as this, after upgrade, in the GoCD server logs:
Caused by: org.h2.jdbc.JdbcSQLNonTransientException: The database is read only; SQL statement: UPDATE PUBLIC.DATABASECHANGELOGLOCK SET LOCKED = TRUE, LOCKEDBY = &#39;10.16.0.5 (10.16.0.5)&#39;, LOCKGRANTED = &#39;2020-06-17 15:07:20.707&#39; WHERE ID = 1 AND LOCKED = FALSE [90097-200] at org.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Enabling GoCD to use MySQL Database</title>
      <link>/installation/configuring_database/mysql.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/installation/configuring_database/mysql.html</guid>
      <description>Enabling GoCD to use MySQL Note: While, support for MySQL is added in GoCD 20.5.0 and a basic round of migration tests has been completed, the functional test suite does not regularly run against MySQL as a part of the build pipeline. This is something to be aware of if moving to MySQL. H2 and PostgreSQL are tested thoroughly as a part of GoCD&amp;rsquo;s build pipelines.
Step 1: Install MySQL Server In order to use MySQL database with GoCD, an external MySQL database server is needed to host the GoCD Server&amp;rsquo;s database.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Enabling GoCD to use PostgreSQL Database</title>
      <link>/installation/configuring_database/postgres.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/installation/configuring_database/postgres.html</guid>
      <description>Enabling GoCD to use PostgreSQL Database Step 1: Install PostgreSQL Server In order to use PostgreSQL database with GoCD, a PostgreSQL database server is needed to host the GoCD Server&amp;rsquo;s database. If the Postgres server is not yet initialized, it needs to be, before GoCD is able to use it. Along with PostgreSQL server, you need to install postgresql-client and postgresql-contrib packages. The postgresql-contrib package contains the citext and pgcrypto module which is necessary for the initial schema creation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>End to end transport security</title>
      <link>/installation/ssl_tls/end_to_end_transport_security.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/installation/ssl_tls/end_to_end_transport_security.html</guid>
      <description>Configure end-to-end transport security Note: To ensure end-to-end transport encryption, please ensure that both your GoCD server and agent are running on atleast version 16.7.0
This section will help you configure and improve the security of the agent-to-server communication using correct SSL/TLS certificates and verification process.
The GoCD agent allows for some configuration to be able to configure and secure the end-to-end transport security to varying security levels.
The agent by default trusts any and all certificates offered to it, which may possibly allow for MITM attacks.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Generic Zip</title>
      <link>/installation/install/agent/zip.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/installation/install/agent/zip.html</guid>
      <description>Advanced installation of GoCD agent using zip installer If you want to run GoCD on a platform which does not have a native installer or want to run GoCD without installing it, you could do so by using the zip installers.
 Download the zip installer for GoCD agent Unzip the installer in a folder of your choice. It creates a subfolder with the name go-agent-${version} Ensure that java executable is available on the PATH environment variable.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Generic Zip</title>
      <link>/installation/install/server/zip.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/installation/install/server/zip.html</guid>
      <description>Advanced installation of GoCD server using zip installer If you want to run GoCD on a platform which does not have a native installer or want to run GoCD without installing it, you could do so by using the zip installers.
 Download the zip installer for GoCD server Unzip the installer in a folder of your choice. It creates a subfolder with the name go-server-${version} Ensure that java executable is available on the PATH environment variable.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>GoCD Database Connection Properties</title>
      <link>/installation/configuring_database/connection-properties.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/installation/configuring_database/connection-properties.html</guid>
      <description>GoCD Database Connection Properties This section describes the configuration properties of the external database server (such as PostgreSQL, MySQL) which GoCD Server will connect and use. Optionally, you can also specify the database SSL config properties for secure communication between GoCD and the database server.
A properties file with the name db.properties needs to be created in the GoCD&amp;rsquo;s configuration directory (config/). The location of GoCD&amp;rsquo;s configuration directory varies per operating system.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hardware Specifications</title>
      <link>/installation/hardware_specifications.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/installation/hardware_specifications.html</guid>
      <description>GoCD hardware specifications The hardware specifications for a GoCD server depends on a number of factors, this makes it difficult to estimate upfront the required hardware specifications and requires a bit of experimentation. The hardware specifications will depend on the current needs and future expansion plans.
 Also see: GoCD system requirements
 Agent hardware requirements The agent hardware requirements are basically determined by the builds that are run. Running GoCD agents will introduce a slight CPU overhead (usually it can be neglected when comparing to the build process CPU requirements).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Installing GoCD Agent</title>
      <link>/installation/installing_go_agent.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/installation/installing_go_agent.html</guid>
      <description>Installing GoCD agent You need to deploy at least one GoCD agent before you can build with GoCD. For the very simplest installation, you can run a GoCD agent on the same machine as your GoCD server.
Before you install the GoCD server or agent, please ensure that you meet the System Requirements.
Choose your operating system  Linux Windows Mac OS X Generic Zip  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Installing GoCD agent on Linux</title>
      <link>/installation/install/agent/linux.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/installation/install/agent/linux.html</guid>
      <description>Installing GoCD agent on Linux Installation of the GoCD agent using the package manager will require root access on the machine.
RPM based distributions (ie RedHat/CentOS/Fedora) The GoCD agent RPM installer has been tested on RedHat Enterprise Linux and CentOS. It should work on most RPM based Linux distributions.
If you prefer to use the YUM repository and install via YUM, paste the following in your shell -
sudo curl https://download.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Installing GoCD agent on Windows</title>
      <link>/installation/install/agent/windows.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/installation/install/agent/windows.html</guid>
      <description>Installing GoCD agent on Windows You must be logged in as a user with Admin privileges to install the GoCD agent on Windows.
 Download a version of go-agent from the downloads page. Double-click the go-agent-${version}-setup.exe installer file and follow the prompts to install Go. During installation you will be asked to select a root path for your GoCD agent. In addition to being the agent installation directory, this directory will contain also contain a directory where your source code is checked out and built.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Installing GoCD Server</title>
      <link>/installation/installing_go_server.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/installation/installing_go_server.html</guid>
      <description>Installing GoCD server Before you install the GoCD server or agent, please ensure that you meet the System Requirements.
Choose your operating system  Linux Windows Mac OS X Generic Zip  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Installing GoCD server on Linux</title>
      <link>/installation/install/server/linux.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/installation/install/server/linux.html</guid>
      <description>Installing GoCD server on Linux Installation of the GoCD server using the package manager will require root access on the machine.
RPM based distributions (ie RedHat/CentOS/Fedora) The GoCD server RPM installer has been tested on RedHat Enterprise Linux and CentOS. It should work on most RPM based Linux distributions.
If you prefer to use the YUM repository and install via YUM, paste the following in your shell -
sudo curl https://download.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Installing GoCD server on Mac OS X</title>
      <link>/installation/install/agent/osx.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/installation/install/agent/osx.html</guid>
      <description>Installing GoCD agent on Mac OS X  Download the Mac OSX installer for GoCD agent from downloads page Unzip the installer in a folder of your choice. It creates a subfolder with the name go-agent-${version}  Managing the GoCD agent process The GoCD agent script must be run with one of the following arguments:
   Script Description     ./bin/go-agent console The GoCD agent will be started in the foreground   .</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Installing GoCD server on Mac OS X</title>
      <link>/installation/install/server/osx.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/installation/install/server/osx.html</guid>
      <description>Installing GoCD server on Mac OS X  Download the Mac OSX installer for GoCD server from downloads page Unzip the installer in a folder of your choice. It creates a subfolder with the name go-server-${version}  Managing the GoCD server process The GoCD server script must be run with one of the following arguments:
   Script Description     ./bin/go-server console The GoCD server will be started in the foreground   .</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Installing GoCD server on Windows</title>
      <link>/installation/install/server/windows.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/installation/install/server/windows.html</guid>
      <description>Installing GoCD server on Windows You must be logged in as a user with Administrator privileges to install the GoCD server on Windows.
 Download a version of go-server from the downloads page. Double-click the go-server-${version}-setup.exe installer file and follow the prompts to install Go. During installation you will be asked to select a directory that will serve as the root path for your GoCD server installation. GoCD server will store all of its associated data in this directory by default You will next be prompted to choose the bundled JRE or specify the location of JRE (or JDK) installed on your system.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Performance Tuning</title>
      <link>/installation/performance_tuning.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/installation/performance_tuning.html</guid>
      <description>GoCD Performance Tuning Capacity Planning This section provides recommendations to evaluate server hardware and memory requirements for your GoCD server. It also highlights some configurations which need to be taken care of when scaling GoCD.
Minimum server requirements The minimum requirements for a GoCD server can be found here
Scaling GoCD As the number of pipelines, agents and concurrent users increase in your setup, GoCD server may have to be scaled up by adding more memory and cores.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>System requirements</title>
      <link>/installation/system_requirements.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/installation/system_requirements.html</guid>
      <description>GoCD System requirements These requirements should meet the needs of most GoCD installations. You may need to allocate additional CPUs and/or memory on the machine hosting the GoCD Server if you intend to use a very large set of pipelines and/or agents.
 Also see: GoCD hardware specifications
 Client (browser) requirements GoCD supports the two most recent versions of the following browsers:
 Google Chrome Mozilla Firefox Microsoft Edge Apple Safari   GoCD Server requirements Hardware  RAM - minimum 1GB, 2GB recommended CPU - minimum 2 cores, 2GHz Disk - minimum 1GB free space  Supported Operating Systems  Windows - Windows Server 2012, Windows Server 2016, Windows 8 and Windows 10 Mac OSX - 10.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Upgrading GoCD</title>
      <link>/installation/upgrading_go.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/installation/upgrading_go.html</guid>
      <description>Upgrading GoCD The steps in this page can be followed to upgrade GoCD. It is recommended to understand any breaking changes between the releases to see if they impact your upgrades in any way.
 Note: If upgrading from a GoCD release &amp;lt;= 20.4.0, there is a the one-time DB migration that needs to be performed as well.
 Before you start   Before you begin upgrading, it is recommended that you turn on maintainance mode on your GoCD server (available since version 19.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Upgrading to GoCD 20.5.0 and higher</title>
      <link>/installation/upgrade_to_gocd_20.5.0.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/installation/upgrade_to_gocd_20.5.0.html</guid>
      <description>Upgrading to GoCD 20.5.0 and higher GoCD 20.5.0 introduced several changes to its database implementation in order to build a more flexible model that allows integrating with multiple databases. As part of these changes GoCD changed the technologies used for automated database migrations (from the unmaintained DBDeploy to Liquibase). These changes require a one-time migration of the GoCD database &amp;lt;= 20.4.0 to one compliant with GoCD 20.5.0 and beyond.
GoCD 20.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>