<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>GoCD User Documentation</title>
    <link>/advanced_usage.html</link>
    <description>Recent content on GoCD User Documentation</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    
	<atom:link href="/advanced_usage/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Agent Health Check API</title>
      <link>/advanced_usage/agent-health-check-api.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/advanced_usage/agent-health-check-api.html</guid>
      <description>Agent Health Check API Note: Using this feature requires atleast version 17.11.0 of the GoCD server and agent.
The health check API allows users to monitor if the agent is connected to the server and is authorized to perform a build.
Configurations The API uses the following configurable agent system properties.
   Property Values     go.agent.status.api.enabled Defaults to true. Set to false to disable health check api end-point   go.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Auto Register a Remote Agent</title>
      <link>/advanced_usage/agent_auto_register.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/advanced_usage/agent_auto_register.html</guid>
      <description>Auto registration of remote agents As a GoCD administrator, you can auto approve remote agents by using a shared key between the GoCD Agent and GoCD Server.
 Add an attribute named &amp;ldquo;agentAutoRegisterKey&amp;rdquo;, for e.g., agentAutoRegisterKey=&amp;ldquo;388b633a88de126531afa41eff9aa69e&amp;rdquo;, in the server configuration fragment, in case it is not present.  &amp;lt;?xml version=&amp;#34;1.0&amp;#34; encoding=&amp;#34;utf-8&amp;#34;?&amp;gt; &amp;lt;cruise xmlns:xsi=&amp;#34;http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance&amp;#34; xsi:noNamespaceSchemaLocation=&amp;#34;cruise-config.xsd&amp;#34; schemaVersion=&amp;#34;75&amp;#34;&amp;gt; &amp;lt;server agentAutoRegisterKey=&amp;#34;388b633a88de126531afa41eff9aa69e&amp;#34;&amp;gt; ... &amp;lt;/cruise&amp;gt;  On the remote GoCD Agent machine, create a file named &amp;lt;agent_installation_directory&amp;gt;/config/autoregister.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Backup GoCD Server</title>
      <link>/advanced_usage/one_click_backup.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/advanced_usage/one_click_backup.html</guid>
      <description>Backup GoCD Server You can use GoCD&amp;rsquo;s administration interface to perform an One-Click Backup of Go. You can also perform the backup using the API.
Steps to initiate backup  On the GoCD Administration page, click on the Backup tab.  Click on &amp;ldquo;BACKUP&amp;rdquo;  Click &amp;ldquo;PROCEED&amp;rdquo; &amp;gt;GoCD will be unusable during the backup process. Backup time is proportional to the database and configuration size. We suggest you backup GoCD when the GoCD Server is idle.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Clean on Task Cancel</title>
      <link>/advanced_usage/dev_clean_up_when_cancel.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/advanced_usage/dev_clean_up_when_cancel.html</guid>
      <description>Clean up after canceling a task When you have jobs that take a long time to run, it is very useful to have the capability to cancel it when you already know it will fail.
By default, GoCD will kill any currently running tasks . There are two other alternatives to this behaviour
 Specify a task to clean up your environment. This could kill the processes and cleanup any existing state.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Command Repository</title>
      <link>/advanced_usage/command_repository.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/advanced_usage/command_repository.html</guid>
      <description>GoCD Command Repository Introduction This feature is an enhancement to Custom Commands in GoCD. Rather than start from scratch with command name and arguments, you now have the option to look up a command from a repository of useful commands maintained by the Go team. The lookup provides a starting point, you may need to edit the arguments, specify a working directory etc. Once saved, the behaviour is the same as a manually entered custom command.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Compare Builds</title>
      <link>/advanced_usage/compare_pipelines.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/advanced_usage/compare_pipelines.html</guid>
      <description>Compare Builds GoCD allows you to compare any two builds of a pipeline and see exactly what changes happened between those two instances. The information in this view will include:
 Code checkins Upstream pipelines Story/defect numbers (when linked to a tracking tool)  Accessing Pipeline Compare There are several locations from where the Pipeline Compare feature can be invoked. These include:
 Pipelines Dashboard page (the &amp;ldquo;Compare&amp;rdquo; link in each pipeline) Environments page Stage Details page Stage History widget within the Stage Details page  Understanding the Pipeline Compare Screen The Pipeline Compare screen lets you compare any two instances of a pipeline.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Conditional Task Execution</title>
      <link>/advanced_usage/dev_conditional_task_execution.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/advanced_usage/dev_conditional_task_execution.html</guid>
      <description>Conditional task execution At times there are certain steps you need to execute only when you know that the build has already failed. For example, when a test suite fails you might want to output additional environment information to the console output
Using web interface Check the appropriate Run if conditions when defining the Task
Using XML configuration Usage: As a developer, I want to run a task only when the build has already failed.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Config Repository</title>
      <link>/advanced_usage/config_repo.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/advanced_usage/config_repo.html</guid>
      <description>GoCD Configuration repository GoCD&amp;rsquo;s configuration is version controlled in a local git repository - config.git hosted on the same machine as the GoCD server. The repo is available at &amp;lt;GoCD server installation directory&amp;gt;/db/config.git. Any changes to the config, either through file-system, API or GoCD configuration UI is saved as a new commit in this repo. This allows auditing of all changes made to the configuration.
NOTE: This repo must not be altered externally as this will lead to errors in GoCD.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fan In</title>
      <link>/advanced_usage/fan_in.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/advanced_usage/fan_in.html</guid>
      <description>GoCD Fan-in Dependency Management GoCD supports fan-in dependency resolution for pipelines that are on auto trigger. Fan-in material resolution will ensure that a pipeline triggers only when all its upstream pipelines have triggered off the same version of an ancestor pipeline or material. This will be the case when you have multiple components building in separate pipelines which all have the same ancestor and you want downstream pipelines to all use the same version of the artifact from the ancestor pipeline.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Graphs</title>
      <link>/advanced_usage/stage_duration_chart.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/advanced_usage/stage_duration_chart.html</guid>
      <description>Graphs Stage Duration Chart GoCD provides a chart on the stage details page which can be used for trend analysis of the stage&amp;rsquo;s periodic runs. This graph shows two line graphs, one each for passed and failed stage instances which are plotted using the total duration of the last 300 stage instances.
To navigate to the Graphs:  Click on the stage bar of the relevant stage on the pipelines dashboard.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Logging</title>
      <link>/advanced_usage/logging.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/advanced_usage/logging.html</guid>
      <description>Logging Introduction You can turn on additional logging to diagnose and troubleshoot issues with the GoCD server and agent.
Log location To change where the GoCD server logs or GoCD agent logs are stored, use the system properties gocd.server.log.dir and gocd.agent.log.dir respectively. Refer to the system properties documentation to find out how to set the system property on the gocd server or agent.
Note: The system property deals with configuring the log location for the GoCD server or agent related logs and not the plugin logs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Maintenance Mode</title>
      <link>/advanced_usage/maintenance_mode.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/advanced_usage/maintenance_mode.html</guid>
      <description>Maintenance Mode Note: Using this feature requires atleast version 19.1.0 of the GoCD server.
The GoCD system includes a lot of internal subsystems and processes, which continuously do work. Some examples include the material subsystem which takes care of polling for materials, the scheduling subsystem which automatically starts pipelines and stages, the agent subsystem which continuously keeps tracks of agent states and provides them jobs to run, etc.
Maintenance mode is a maintenance mode which can be utilized by the GoCD system administrator to safely restart or upgrade the GoCD server without having any running jobs reschedule when the server is back up.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Multiple Agents on One Machine</title>
      <link>/advanced_usage/admin_install_multiple_agents.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/advanced_usage/admin_install_multiple_agents.html</guid>
      <description>Install multiple agents on the same machine In order to fully utilize your hardware, it is often useful to install multiple agents on a single machine.
Currently GoCD installers do not support this out of the box. The following sections describe how this can be done manually
Windows On Windows, multiple GoCD agents can be run in two ways - as Windows service or as a Windows command
Running as Windows service  Install your first agent with the installer to the default location Copy the installation folder (&amp;ldquo;C:\Program Files\Go Agent&amp;rdquo;) to &amp;ldquo;C:\Program Files\Go Agent 2&amp;rdquo; Delete the file C:\Program Files\Go Agent 2\config\guid.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Other Config Options</title>
      <link>/advanced_usage/other_config_options.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/advanced_usage/other_config_options.html</guid>
      <description>Other config options This is a list of some of the more advanced configuration options available. These will typically need to be set before the start of the GoCD Server, unless specified.
How to set these options Environment variables If an option specified below is of type &amp;ldquo;Environment Variable&amp;rdquo;, then it needs to be made available to the GoCD Server in a way that is specified by the operating system (or distribution).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pipelines as code</title>
      <link>/advanced_usage/pipelines_as_code.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/advanced_usage/pipelines_as_code.html</guid>
      <description>Pipelines as code GoCD supports storing pipeline configuration in a source code repository, either with your application code or in a separate repository all on its own. It allows you to move it out of GoCD so that you can modify, control and version it externally. Such modifications will be seen by a periodic poller in the GoCD server and it will merge those pipeline configurations into the pipelines it finds in the main configuration XML file.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Properties</title>
      <link>/advanced_usage/properties.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/advanced_usage/properties.html</guid>
      <description>Properties Introduction Properties provide a simple way of collecting metrics over time. GoCD sets some standard properties for you. You can also set properties yourself using the Go REST APIs (see Properties API for more information). GoCD also allows you to download the history of your job in a convenient CSV format, so that you can analyse the results in spreadsheets or scripts.
Property history GoCD allows you to download the history of properties that you have defined.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Spawn multiple instances of a Job</title>
      <link>/advanced_usage/admin_spawn_multiple_jobs.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/advanced_usage/admin_spawn_multiple_jobs.html</guid>
      <description>Run a Job on a group of Agents Sometimes there is a particular job that you may wish to run on all agents in an environment, or in all agents that match a certain resource tag. For example you may want to run a system update on all linux agents, or install a new piece of software.
GoCD will run the Job on all agents that match the environment and resources specified in the job.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Timer Based GoCD Server Backup</title>
      <link>/advanced_usage/cron_backup.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/advanced_usage/cron_backup.html</guid>
      <description>Perform GoCD server backups on a schedule To run a GoCD server backup at a given time, use a timer. Timers understand a cron-like specification for when to perform a backup. The GoCD server can be optionally configured to invoke a post-backup script to allow you to copy the backup to an external machine or service (like AWS&amp;rsquo; S3).
The post backup script The post backup script, if configured, will be invoked regardless of success or failure of the script, and will receive the following environment variables:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Trigger With Options</title>
      <link>/advanced_usage/trigger_with_options.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/advanced_usage/trigger_with_options.html</guid>
      <description>Trigger with a different revision of material GoCD supports a Trigger with option that allows you to run the pipeline with a specific revision of the material(s).
Trigger with options Information The following information are displayed for the last 5 revisions. For an SCM material, the following information is shown
 Revision hash or pipeline label Committer Check-in comment for the revision Check-in time of the revision  For a pipeline material, the pipeline label and the corresponding run time is shown</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>